IIC Prudential I Protect Smart
Plus looks like a very feature-loaded
term plan on paper, but
let's
review this video to see if this plan is as comprehensive as it looks on paper.
Apart from critical illness return of premiums,
many benefits like zero cost exit are also being provided
.  You too must be
getting a lot of messages on your WhatsApp. If you
are currently looking for life insurance policies, does this plan really
provide that much flexibility?
Will it also be affordable?  Let's review this video to see if it provides
you with benefits that are appropriate for your life stage
.  Hello everyone, I am
Ajith, welcome to Dito Insurance. 9
Locks Plus has helped Indians choose the right term
plan
.  There will be no Pam, no heart-selling
either.  As a Jaroda Banked Company, we
provide one-on-one honest guidance with IRDI certified advisors
.
If you need a right term plan that is right for your case,
the link is in the description.
Book a free call.  So first, let's
start with the insurer's background
.  ICI Prudential Life is a joint venture with ICI
Bank and Prudential Corporation
.  It has
also been listed on Indian exchanges since 2016
.  So this company provides us with options, especially term
ULIP endowment and NUT plans
.
[Music] So you could say there's a wide product mix
.  Along with that, they are
also providing a strong digital ecosystem
.  And they are
also consistently bringing innovative features
to the market.  So if you want to
see an overall snapshot of this company's performance, we have a
claim settlement ratio of
98% on average for the last three years.  Along with that,
our amount settlement ratio is also
around 95%.  And they are maintaining a robust
annual business
.
They are doing business worth around Rs 19,774 crores.  And the
complaints volume is
11 complaints
registered for every 10,000 claims.  Complaints
may be slightly higher than industry leaders,
but overall, the
company's metrics
are solid.  And along with that, the solvency
ratio is also more than 2.  This means that the
usual IRDI benchmark should be
more than 1.5.  So, if we look at the
eligibility and basic features of this policy, the
entry age limitation is
between 18 and 65 years.  So if you think your
age is in between, you
can consider this policy.  And
we also have single pay,
limited pay, and regular pay options for premium payment tenure
.  You can also
pay monthly, semi-annually, or even
once annually.  And if we
want to take this policy, we must be either a salaried
individual or
self-employed.
Because we do both medical and
financial underwriting
.  We have primarily three options in this policy
.  First Life
Option: If you select this option, in the event of the
death of the insured member, a lump sum will be
paid out to the nominee.  The second
option is the Life Plus option.  So this
includes a death benefit as well as an accidental death benefit.  In case of
accidental death, we will be provided with
more coverage than the Sum Assur we already have,
thanks to this accidental death benefit add-on.  Another
option is the life relensing
option.  So, accidental death benefit is provided for the first 10 years
.  From then on, only basic cover will be
provided.  For now,
however, this lost variant is no longer alive.
And if we look at the built-in features in this policy,
we are provided with a terminal illness benefit
.  This means that if the life
expectancy is six months or
less, after confirmation by two doctors,
we will be provided with the full sum insured
as a payout,
and this policy also includes life stage protection
.  If you get married after taking out a policy,
you
have the chance to increase your sum insured by up to 50%.   It can
be increased by 25% for the birth of the first child and another 25% for the birth of the second child.  And in addition, if you
take a home loan, you can increase the
cover amount up to 100% at the time of disbursement
.  Otherwise, if
you want to take this, you must be under 50 and
select the regular pay option along with it.  If you
ever want to increase the cover amount, the
terms and conditions
are based on underwriting.
And along with that, we
also have a smart exit option in this policy.  So,
you
can avail this option after the completion of the 25-year policy tenure.
Otherwise, your age must be less than 60.
You cannot select this option in the last five years
.
Another unique feature in this policy is the premium break.  So even if
you want to
defer the policy premium for one year after five years, you
can do so.  And this feature
cannot be used in the last three policy years.  And if
you want two premium breaks,
you will need to have a gap of at least five years between these two premium breaks
.  But when you
repay the premiums [music],
then we have to pay the deferred premiums as well as the
next year's premiums due
.  And
we
can use this benefit multiple times during the policy lifetime.
[Music] And another feature is the
option called Insta Pay Out.
So for example, if you
have taken a cover amount of 1 crore, you will be
paid up to 3 lakhs within one working day of submitting your claim documents. If
not immediately,
there is a minimum waiting period of three years to avail this option.
And if we look at the riders in this policy,
we have a critical illness rider in the optional add-on benefits
.  So, you are
covered for 20 or 60 illnesses
.  If any of these 20 or 60
illnesses are diagnosed, we will be
given a lump sum payout.  So this
payout has nothing to do with our base cover amount
.  This works like over and above coverage
.  However, there is a
90-day waiting period for this payout
from the time we take out the policy,
and there is also a 15-day survival
period.  And this benefit
only provides a rider term of up to 20 years
.  So the
second rider in this policy is the accidental death benefit
rider.  If the insured
member dies due to an accident, you will be paid an additional benefit on top of your base sum insured
.  But this rider benefit
only covers accidents.   There is no
coverage for other types of deaths
.  And
most often we would suggest skipping this rider because of the limited coverage option
.  And if we
look at the discounts in this policy, we are
providing discounts of up to 12.5% ​​and up to 5% in the first year when salaried individuals switch to regular pay.  And if you
select the limited pay option, there will
be a discount of up to 15%.  And
online or digital discounts are provided to us, ranging from 1 to
5%.
These discounts vary depending on the age of the insured and the frequency of coverage
.  And this
policy also provides us with multiple payout options
.  This means that
we
can select any amount of bonus at the time of receiving the nominee.  This means that the
full amount is given to the nominee at once
.  Or there is also an income option.
That means 10% is given every year.  They will provide you with
full coverage for 10 years
.  Or if you
think you want a mix, there's also a lump sum plus income
benefit.  So some people will
give you a percentage immediately and provide the remaining percentage over the next
10 years
.  And another option is
increasing income.  So,
if you have 10% growth every year, they will provide you with a payout
.  So overall, you will be provided with coverage of 145% of the
sum insured.   If
you select this option.   As
usual, we recommend taking out liability coverage if you are in Ditto
.  Because
if there are any deaths, if you
want to make any investments, or if you have
big expenses, it will
be easy to manage.
We
can also see premium examples of how IIC has positioned this plan.  If you pause this video here and
watch it, you will get a premiums comparison
.  If we look at the premiums, we can
say that they are more affordable than HDFC.   There
are a little more than Batbabaz M Max.  If you want to take this policy,
you will get most of the benefits provided by
this policy with a coverage of Rs 2 crores or above, but don't
consider the price alone.  It's better to consider the
features you get in addition to the price and
then
take a policy.  Overall, we recommend this policy to
anyone who
wants flexibility in their term insurance policy.  In addition,
if you want benefits like smart exit, premium break, and life stage upgrades, you can definitely
consider this policy.  And the
critical illness rider in this policy
provides us with payouts even for some major serious conditions
.  So that can also
be said to be a definite advantage.  As
mentioned earlier, this policy provides us with
structured legacy planning
.  This means that we can customize the payout as
we want, based on our needs and conditions,
so
that also provides you with flexibility
.  But if we
look at the considerations in this policy, we see that
IICI has slightly more
complaints registered.  So it's
better for you to maintain the documentation very clean.
Read the exclusions and rider terms and conditions carefully before
taking out the policy.  Because there are things
like waiting periods and survival cases
.  And as mentioned earlier, this
policy may not be the most economical policy in the market
.  Otherwise, it provides a very strong overall value
for the features you get plus the flexibility
.  So, when you are thinking about
how to structure your cover amount when taking out insurance,
set a target of 15 to 20 times your annual income.  Because
after adding up all your liabilities and future goals, this much income might be
enough for you.  And along with that, you should take out
term insurance up to
your retirement age or the age at which
you will have financial dependence
.  And
if you want to lock in premiums for the payment term, you
can consider Limited Pay.  Or it's
better to stick to regular pay.  It is better to take a Yed On which provides
critical illness coverage for 60 illnesses in riders
.  And it's better to skip the accidental death benefit
.  But
before you take out your term insurance,
make a quick checklist.
First thing is, when you fill out the proposal form, it is
better to state all your declarations very clearly.  Fill in all your health
conditions and lifestyle details
honestly.  And
along with that, take some precautions while filling your nominee details
.  And it's better to link your insurance account and
also enable auto debit.  So
you will not have to defer premiums in the future
.  And share the claims
documentation list with your family
.  But if you still feel that I Protect Smart is right for you based on your income,
liabilities, dependencies, and health
profile,
book a free consultation.
There is a link in the description.  So we
can give you a custom blueprint
based on your needs.  So overall, term
insurance, even if simple, will
provide you with the highest value if it is designed thoughtfully.  So if you found this breakdown
useful, like, share and
subscribe.
Your support will help us a lot in spreading financial literacy
.  See you again in the next video
.  Happy insurance hunting.